<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>NULLPOINTER</title>
    <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website" />
    <updated>2025-10-04T12:09:14+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>me</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website</id>

    <entry>
        <title>About My Academic Practice</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/about-my-academic-practice.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/about-my-academic-practice.html</id>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T11:57:23+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Presenting my work at the Museo Tamayo, Mexico City I am an&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/9/mexico1.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="534" sizes="(min-width: 760px) 660px, calc(93.18vw - 30px)" srcset="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/9/responsive/mexico1-xs.jpg 320w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/9/responsive/mexico1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/9/responsive/mexico1-md.jpg 768w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/9/responsive/mexico1-xl.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p><br><em>Presenting my work at the Museo Tamayo, Mexico City</em></p>
<p>I am an experienced lecturer and academic with a PhD exploring “the digital sublime in videogames”. This research investigates the philosophical and conceptual considerations of using procedural generation and generative processes in game design. Some of the technical research i produced for my thesis is available <a href="http://www.nullpointer.co.uk/content/category/tech-2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>, and the games I produced for the PhD are covered <a href="http://www.nullpointer.co.uk/content/completed-games/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>In parallel to working on my PhD I also taught at The University of Huddersfield as a cross-department practicing lecturer between the school of Art,Design &amp; Architecture and the school of Computing. In this role i taught a range of modules from foundation programming (xna/unity) to Critical Game theory. During this time i also provided tutorial support and workshops for the students. Since that time I have been a visiting lecturer for both the University of Sussex and The University of Brighton.</p>
<p>I have contributed to various publications and conferences including a chapter on procedural generation for the <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Handbook-Digital-Games-Marios-Angelides/dp/1118328035" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Handbook Of Digital Games</a>, and a paper on Gestalt perception for <a href="http://www.digra.org/digital-library/authors/betts-tom/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">DIGRA</a>. I have delivered varioustalks for Universities, professional groups and musuems, including presenting at GDC (San Francisco), FreePlay (Melbourne), The Bartlett (London) and Unite (Malmo).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About The Games</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/nullpointer-games.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/nullpointer-games.html</id>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T11:55:28+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I have over 10 years of design and programming experience, working for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/8/NP_logo_NoSubtitle.png" alt="" width="840" height="504" sizes="(min-width: 760px) 660px, calc(93.18vw - 30px)" srcset="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/8/responsive/NP_logo_NoSubtitle-xs.png 320w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/8/responsive/NP_logo_NoSubtitle-sm.png 480w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/8/responsive/NP_logo_NoSubtitle-md.png 768w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/8/responsive/NP_logo_NoSubtitle-xl.png 1024w"></figure>
<p>I have over 10 years of design and programming experience, working for Big-Robot ltd, producing client driven projects, teaching game design at University level and creating cutting edge game-projects for Phd research. I work mainly in Unity, but I also have experience of working with c++, openframeworks, developing for Ios &amp; Android platforms and Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>I have worked on many aspects of design and programming including; AI, UI, UX, level design, VFX, sound design, game mechanics, physics, animation, shaders. I have produced several projects as a solo developer, but I am also used to working in teams, directing art/sound/animation, defining additional programming, managing production, workflow, testing, releases and repositories.</p>
<p>I have given presentations about creative coding and game design at various international venues including GDC (San Francisco), Indievelopment (Amsterdam), Rezzed (UK). I have a Phd in philosophy &amp; game design and have a specific interest in procedural generation and generative art.</p>
<p>The games listed below each have their own info page (on steam/itch etc), but more info is also available on request.</p>
<div class="fluid-width-video-wrapper"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZsxS8EntqOM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" name="fitvid0" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<p><br><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/853240/The_Light_Keeps_Us_Safe/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">THE LIGHT KEEPS US SAFE</a></p>
<p>The Light Keeps Us Safe is a procedurally-generated apocalypse in which only The Light can save us. Use stealth and evasion to avoid terrifying machines that patrol the desolate world, and employ the powers of Light to unpick their deadly traps. Early access, due for release 2019</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/853240/The_Light_Keeps_Us_Safe/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on Steam</a></p>
<div class="fluid-width-video-wrapper"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Xqw5EQ0j7Po" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" name="fitvid1" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<p><br><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/457760/The_Signal_From_Tlva/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">THE SIGNAL FROM TOLVA</a></p>
<p>The Signal From Tölva is an open-world first-person shooter set on a distant, haunted, future world. Unlock savage weapons and recruit robots to fight alongside you as rival factions struggle to discover the source of the mysterious signal. What you discover will decide the fate of a world.</p>
<p>“A lean, intelligent sci-fi shooter with a watchmaker’s eye for detail.”<br><em>80% – PC Gamer</em></p>
<p>“An open-world wasteland game of unusual profundity.”<br><em>Eurogamer</em></p>
<p>“It’s like being gently hugged by a strange cloud that occasionally fires lasers.”<br><em>Cool Ghosts</em><br><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/457760/The_Signal_From_Tlva/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on Steam</a></p>
<div class="fluid-width-video-wrapper"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/akrT77X-IZA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" name="fitvid2" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<p><br><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/242880/Sir_You_Are_Being_Hunted/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">SIR YOU ARE BEING HUNTED</a></p>
<p>Sir, You Are Being Hunted is a procedurally-generated British horror in which tweed-wearing robots hunt you for sport. Roam the landscape, scavenge for food, hide breathlessly in the undergrowth, flee in terror, and even fight back with stolen weapons.</p>
<p>Sir is a stealth and survival game unlike any other, set on a mysterious archipelago generated procedurally by you, and therefore unique to each game you play. You can define your own islands, each one created in moments by our rather clever British Countryside Generator. These islands are then populated by a raving aristocracy of murderous robots, their robot hounds, and worse. You job is simply to survive, and get home.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/242880/Sir_You_Are_Being_Hunted/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on Steam</a></p>
<div class="fluid-width-video-wrapper"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/nvVdMr6ox9A" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" name="fitvid3" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<p><br><a href="https://tomnullpointer.itch.io/permutation-racer" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PERMUTATION RACER</a></p>
<p>Permutation Racer’ is an experimental, endless racing game, exploring the procedural construction of space.</p>
<p>It’s part of my PHD research to investigate ideas that connect games, permutation and the sublime. The race track is generated from a series of noise filtered ‘biome’ styling functions. There are about 12 region types ranging from chasms to archways and caves, all generated in real time as the player progresses. I might post a more technical article about the actual methods used later. The only aim is to travel as far as possible, hampered by the fact that over time/distance the generation algorithms make the track more hazardous and convoluted.</p>
<p><a href="https://tomnullpointer.itch.io/permutation-racer" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on itch.io</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1hZ2UvNDk1NDQvMjE3MDA0LmpwZw==/original/mGvqB%2F.jpg" alt="screenshot" width="100%" data-is-external-image="true"></p>
<p><a href="https://tomnullpointer.itch.io/in-ruins" rel="noopener" target="_blank">IN RUINS</a></p>
<p>‘In Ruins’ is an experimental, ambient game examining the procedural construction of space. It’s part of an ongoing Phd research project to investigate ideas that connect games, permutation and the sublime. It’s part of a series of games inspired by artistic interpretations of the sublime, in this case the work of Romantic landscape painters (Thomas Cole, Caspar David Friedrich etc). Its also heavily influenced by Fumito Uedas Ico series.</p>
<p>The player is deposited on the edge of a procedurally generated island. The island consists of overgrown pathways ruined spires and broken ramparts. A central tower looms above the island beckoning the player towards it.</p>
<p><a href="https://tomnullpointer.itch.io/in-ruins" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on itch.io</a></p>
<div class="fluid-width-video-wrapper"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/AfEvwkz8uMI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" name="fitvid4" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></div>
<p><br><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/207670/AVSEQ/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">AVSEQ</a></p>
<p>AVSEQ is an audio-visual sequencer puzzle game. Connect falling atoms to unlock near-endless varieties of music at each stage. Every level of AVSEQ is a music sequencer with 2.2300745198530623×10^43 possible audio permutations, that’s 22 tredecillion in total!</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/207670/AVSEQ/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Available on Steam</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Nullpointer</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/about-me-post.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/about-me-post.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/7/instapic.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T11:49:01+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/7/instapic.png" alt="" />
                    Tom Betts, aka Nullpointer, is an artist, academic and coder with a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/7/instapic.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Tom Betts, aka Nullpointer, is an artist, academic and coder with a PhD exploring “the digital sublime in videogames”. He was the lead programmer at game development studio <a href="http://www.big-robot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Big Robot</a>, responsible for games such as “Sir, You are being Hunted”, “The Signal From Tolva” and “The light will keep us safe”. Now he runs his own game development studio Nullpointer Games.</p>
<p>He is a published musician, and has performed and delivered talks at international events such as DIGRA, FreePlay, UNITE, Sonar, Rezzed and Indievelopment. He has shown his digital artwork at the ICA, ZKM, New museum(NY) and the Rotterdam film festival and has worked on projects for the Tate, V&amp;A and Southbank Centre. He likes generative systems, green tea, watching films where nothing much happens, the colour grey and ironing.</p>
<p>On this site you can find a semi-regular feed of proc-gen experiments and information on completed games.</p>
<p>You can find him on bluesky at @tomnullpointer. Some older material is still available on <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/tomnullpointer">youtube</a> and <a href="http://vimeo.com/user1356993">vimeo</a> and the old nullpointer site is archived <a href="http://www.nullpointer.co.uk/-/home.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a> (more details on my art career and some music stuff)</p>
<p>You can contact me at the obvious email address (This is my website, my name is tom).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Post3</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-post-3.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-post-3.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/4/instapic.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="DevBlog"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T10:52:59+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/4/instapic.png" alt="" />
                    This post outlines some of the technical issues and solutions connected with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/4/instapic.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This post outlines some of the technical issues and solutions connected with the development of Permutation Racer, the third game produced for my PhD research.</p>
<p>Permutation Racer is an experimental, endless racing game, exploring the procedural construction of space.<br>It’s part of an ongoing investigation of ideas that connect games, permutation and the sublime. The race track is generated from a series of noise filtered ‘biome’ styling functions. There are about 12 region types ranging from chasms to archways and caves, all generated in real time as the player progresses. The objective is simply to travel as far as possible. More generalised information about the game and a download of the software is <a href="https://tomnullpointer.itch.io/permutation-racer">available at this link</a>. A description of the approach developed for Permutation Racer is outlined below.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Post 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-post-2.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-post-2.html</id>
            <category term="DevBlog"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T10:52:54+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Post 1</title>
        <author>
            <name>me</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-page-what-is-this.html"/>
        <id>https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/new-page-what-is-this.html</id>
            <category term="DevBlog"/>

        <updated>2025-10-04T10:47:08+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    An example of a blog post that i might add over time
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>An example of a blog post that i might add over time</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/1/TomBetts2.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="640" sizes="(min-width: 760px) 660px, calc(93.18vw - 30px)" srcset="https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/1/responsive/TomBetts2-xs.jpg 320w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/1/responsive/TomBetts2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/1/responsive/TomBetts2-md.jpg 768w ,https://tomnullpointer.github.io/website/media/posts/1/responsive/TomBetts2-xl.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
